Abhishek Mhatre

UX Experience Research/UX Design/UI Design/Product Design

Searching for a job as a User Experience Research, UX designer, Full Spectrum Product designer UI designer, UI/UX designer. A graduate Designer in HCI (Human Computer Interaction) with attention to detial. I love to ask "How" and "Why" questions for a better innovative research and design strategy.



https://github.com/ abhisheksuhasmhatre



www.linkedin.com/in/abhisheksuhasmhatre



+1-585-662-8823



abhishekmhatre17@gmail.com



https://
abhisheksuhasmhatre.github.io/
abhisheksmhatre.github.io/
index.html#home



https://
abhisheksuhasmhatre.github.io/



https://dribbble.com/ abhisheksuhasmhatre

Skills

Agile Methodology, Web Design, User Experience, User Interface Design, Usability Testing, User Centered Design, User Experiene Design

Tools

Illustrator, Affinity Designer, Photoshop, Axure RP 8, Sketch, ProtoApp, 123D Design, Cure, Microsoft Office, Eclipse, PyCharm, BalsamiQ Mockups, Figma, Weka, R-Studio, Weka, R-Studio

Programming

HTML 5, CSS3, Bootstrap, Three.JS, Paperj.JS, PHP Forms, JavaScript, JQuery, Java, JASON, Particle Photon

Other

Workpress

Technologies

Internet of Things, Machine Learning, 3D Printing, Laser Cutting, Machine Learning

OS

Mac Windows Linux

Experience

Free Lance Product Designer, NGO - Gomasu Development Foundationn | March 2017 - Present

Designing Logo, Business Cards, Website, Reports, Certificates for an NGO - GOMASU Development Foundation. A complete product design.

Achievements - Gained more knowledge in Card Sorting, Logo Design,

Product Design Process, Mind Mapping, User Flow, Agile Technology (Mixer of Scrums and Kanban Frameworks).

Teaching Assistant, RIT Dr. Prof. Peter Lutz | August - December 2016 Tutor and grader for Java

Research Assistant, RIT Dr. Prof. Matt Huenerfauth | Jannuary 2014 - Present Data analysis on data from eye tracker system. Using Weka a machine learning software, analyzing data from different participants.

Achievements - Gained more knowledge in Machine Learning Skills, Weka, R-Studio.

Junior Engineer, Omtech Enterprises | June 2013 - July 2014

Quality control engineer • Wireless Communication • Robotics • PLC • SCADA • HMI

Internship, AIR INDIA | June - July 2012

Boeing B747-400, B777-200LR, B777-300ER, B737-800 and A310- 300 • Accessories department in Avionics department, over cable components, power sources, etc.

Education

ROCHESTER INSTITUTE OF TECHNOLOGY

MS Majoring in Human Computer Interaction Specializing in UI/UX | GPA 4, CGPA 3.5

August 2014 - July 2017 | Rochester, NY

Projects

PokemonGo Website (Front End) | Jannuary - March 2017 HTML5 • CSS3 • JavaScript • AngularJS 2

Redcom SIGMA Calling Windows App (UI/UX In Progress) | Jannuary - May 2017 Contextual Enquiry • Work Flow • Affinity Diagram • Personas • Low-Fi Prototype • High-Fi Prototype

Achievements - Usability Testing, Leaned more about Morae Software.

• Conducted Heuristic Evaluation on the product • Prepared a Tesrt Plan and Conducted Interviews with participants • Decoded the videos recordings of participants using Morae software • Confirmed our findings and made a final report.

LinkedIn OS App Redesign (UI/UX In Progress) | Jannuary - May 2017 Contextual Enquiry • Work Flow • Affinity Diagram • Personas • Low-Fi Prototype

Achievements - Better Knowledge in User Centered Design, Demographics, Cultural Models, Sequence Models, Artifact Models, Flow Model, Visiong Diagram.

• Conducted Heuristic Evaluation on the product and conducted interviews • Made the Affinity Models, cultural, flow, sequence models • Prepared storyboarding scenarios and visioning diagrams.

IoT Projects (Front End & Back End) | AUGUST - December 2016

3 Projects • Particle Photon • C++ • HTML5 • CSS3 • JQuery • JavaScript • three.JS • paper.JS • Laser Cutting • 3D Printing • Work on Fabric

HTML Projects (Front End) | August - December 2016 3 Projects • HTML5 • CSS3 • Bootstrap • JQuery • JavaScript • PHP • three.JS • Responsive Website

Slackless App Prototype (UI/UX) | Jannuary - May 2016

Contextual Enquiry • Affinity Diagram • Personas • Low-Fi Prototype High-Fi Prototype. Link: https://avsiid.wordpress.com

Achievements - Learned more about Contextual Inquiry, Affinity Diagram, in Vision.

• Conducted interviews • Made the Affinity Models and personas • Made lowfi prototypes with pen and whiteboard, high-fi prototypes with the help of Illustrator and inVision.

Parking Lot Design (UI/UX) | August - December 2015

Contextual Enquiry • Personas • Report

Achievements - Learned more about forming more open ended interview questions leading to information specific questions.

• Conducted Observatgions and interviews • Made personas • Made Storyboarding and Scenarios.